Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/alison-trucnguyen (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Web Testing
API Testing
Project Coordination

Languages

Vietnamese (Native or Bilingual)
English (Limited Working)
Spanish (Limited Working)

Certifications

Applied Data Science
Google Advanced Data Analytics
Software Automation Testing
Data Science Math Skills
Data Science Professional
Certificate

Honors-Awards

Christmas cards design competition Winner of the writing contest "Learn Spanish & enjoy life - Volume I"

Nguyen Ngoc Thanh Truc

Software Engineer Analyst

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Summary

Software Tester with demonstrated experience in manual and automation testing for web and mobile applications. Linguistics Professional with a Bachelor's Degree in Spanish Literature and Linguistics from Ho Chi Minh University of Social Sciences and Humanities.

Experience

DXC Technology Software Tester September 2024 - Present (7 months) Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Rockship

Software Tester

June 2024 - September 2024 (4 months)

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

- Analyze and verify business requirement.
- Execute manual and API testing for web and Android/iOS mobile app.
- Log bug and create test report

Bear Lab

Software Tester, Project Coordinator May 2023 - May 2024 (1 year 1 month) Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

- Analyze and verify business requirement.

- 110 Oth Willin Oity, Victilain
- Execute manual and API testing for web and Android/iOS mobile app.
- Write checklist, test cases and test reports for features.
- Keep tracking of tasks to ensure release date by using Jira, Confluence, Trello.
- Report data collection and analysis through SQL Server, Google Analytics, Mixpanel.
- Customize AI chatbot conversation and UI (Chatbot.com, LiveChat).
- Assist PM on project scope, planning and relevant documents.

CMC Global Company Limited.

Software Tester

December 2022 - May 2023 (6 months)

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

- Execute manual, API testing to locate bugs and regressions to ensure product with standard quality.
- Design and write test automation scripts in Java by using a test automation framework.
- Work and investigate problems with software developers to find solutions as a result of testing.
- Data collection and checking in DB (SQL Server).
- Experience in automated testing tools/frameworks (Postman, Selenium, Appium, JUnit, Cucumber).
- Experience working in an Agile/Scrum Development process.

Ureka Media

Manual Tester

October 2022 - December 2022 (3 months)

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

- Execute test cases, plan and estimate tasks, share efforts with other team members.
- Perform functional testing, UAT and regression testing.
- Investigate problems, raise and verify bugs to make sure applications work correctly.

Technical Service Center 4 - National Power Transmission

Corporation 4

Administrative Assistant

December 2021 - June 2022 (7 months)

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

- Schedule and coordinate meetings, interviews, events, and reservations as needed.
- Politely converse with guests and respond to all inquiries.
- Answer incoming phone calls and prepare outgoing mail and correspondence.
- Carry out administrative duties such as filing, typing, copying, binding, scanning, etc.

Education

UNIVERSITY OF SOCIAL SCIENCES AND HUMANITIES (USSH)

Bachelor's degree, Spanish Linguistics and Literature · (September 2017 - June 2023)